// Array of questions with options and correct answers
const questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "A Fahrenheit thermometer indicates a temperature of ‘ 14°F. its corresponding reading on the Celsius scale will be ______?",
    answer: "– 10°C",
    options: [
      "+ 10°C",
      "+ 20°C",
      "– 10°C",
      "– 2O°C"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "A satellite moving round the earth with a uniform speed has _________?",
    answer: "Uniform acceleration",
    options: [
      "Uniform acceleration",
      "Uneven acceleration",
      "An accelerated motion",
      "No acceleration at all"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The biggest planet in our solar system is ________?",
    answer: "Jupiter",
    options: [
      "Venus",
      "Pluto",
      "Jupiter",
      "N.O.T"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Anti Diuretic hormone is secreted by one of the following glands?",
    answer: "Pituitary",
    options: [
      "Pituitary",
      "Pancreas",
      "Thyroid",
      "N.O.T"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "One of the following countries produces maximum energy from atomic reactors?",
    answer: "USA",
    options: [
      "UK",
      "USA",
      "France",
      "N.O.T"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Serum if blood plasma minus its? ",
    answer: "Clotting proteins ",
    options: [
      "Calcium ions",
      "Globulins",
      "Clotting proteins ",
      "N.O.T"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Steering of a car involves?",
    answer: "A pair of forces acting along the same line and in opposite direction",
    options: [
      "A single force",
      "Two forces acting in the same direction",
      "Two forces acting along different lines and in opposite direction",
      "A pair of forces acting along the same line and in opposite direction"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "All matter is made of _________? ",
    answer: "Atoms",
    options: [
      "Vibrations",
      "Atoms",
      "Water",
      "Air"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The soul of chemistry is dealing with _______?",
    answer: "Composition and properties of matter",
    options: [
      "Internal structural changes in matter",
      "Composition of matter",
      "Properties of matter",
      "Composition and properties of matter"
    ]
    },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Moon light reaches to earth in __________ seconds?",
    answer: "1.3 seconds",
    options: [
      "0.3 seconds",
      "1.3 seconds",
      "2.3 seconds",
      "3.3 seconds"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The study Of GLANDS is called?",
    answer: "Endocrinology",
    options: [
      "Cardiology",
      "Entomology",
      "Endocrinology",
      "N.O.T"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Sodium carbonate is produced by ________?",
    answer: "Amonia solvay process",
    options: [
      "Amonia solvay process",
      "Haber Process",
      "Decons Process",
      "Lead Chamber Process"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which of the following planets is known as “morning star”? ",
    answer: "Venus",
    options: [
      "Mercury",
      "Mars",
      "Venus",
      "Saturn"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "In the manufacture of banaspati ghee the gas used is ________?",
    answer: "Hydrogen",
    options: [
      "Helium",
      "Hydrogen",
      "Oxygen",
      "Nitrogen"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "A pulsar is a rapidly spinning neutron star which emits:",
    answer: "Radio waves detectable from Earth",
    options: [
      "A blinding light when it aligns with the planets",
      "A gravitational pull which attracts high energy dust particles",
      "Enough energy to power itself indefinitely",
      "Radio waves detectable from Earth"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "What are the names of the two stars in the Big Dipper used to locate Polaris?",
    answer: "The Pointer Stars",
    options: [
      "The Pointer Stars",
      "The North Seekers",
      "The Pointer Sisters",
      "N.O.T"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "The average speed of a moving object during a given interval of time is always:",
    answer: "The distance covered during the time interval divided by the time interval",
    options: [
      "The magnitude of its average velocity over the interval",
      "The distance covered during the time interval divided by the time interval",
      "One-half its speed at the end of the interval",
      "Its acceleration multiplied by the time interval"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Color of the glow produced in the discharge tube:",
    answer: "Depends on the gas used in the discharge tube",
    options: [
      "Depends on the pressure in the discharge tube",
      "Depends on the metal used as cathode",
      "Depends on the gas used in the discharge tube",
      "Does not depend on the nature of the gas used in the discharge tube"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "The amount of energy required by the children of age between one to three years is _________?",
    answer: "1200 k Calories ",
    options: [
      "300 k Calories",
      "600 k Calories",
      "900 k Calories",
      "1200 k Calories "
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "The season changes because of the ________?",
    answer: "Earth is revolving round the sun",
    options: [
      "Moon is revolving round the earth",
      "Earth is revolving round its axis",
      "Earth is revolving round the sun",
      "Planet Mars is attracting the sun"
    ]
  },
];
